MATTEO PEZZULLA

@ matt@mpe.au.dk
mpezzulla.com
Skype ID: matteo.pezzulla

ÅRHUS, DK

Date of Birth: August 3, 1988

CITIZENSHIP: Italian

Summary of qualifications & assets

I am an Assistant Professor in the Department of Mechanical Engineering at Aarhus University.

My current research involves aspects of fluid-structure interactions and the theoretical and applied mechanics of thin shells. I work among solid mechanics, fluid mechanics, and differential geometry and I am interested in analytical, numerical, and experimental methods.

I am a member of the American Physical Society (APS).

Experience

Nov 2017 – Oct 2020 POSTDOCTORAL ASSOCIATE at École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne Supervisor: Prof. Pedro M. Reis

Nov 2015 – Oct 2017 POSTDOCTORAL ASSOCIATE at Boston University Supervisor: Prof. Douglas P. Holmes

EDUCATION

FEBRUARY 2016 Ph.D. in THEORETICAL AND APPLIED MECHANICS,

Sapienza - Università di Roma

with honors

Focus: Morphing of Thin Soft Structures Driven by Geometry and Swelling

Advisor: Prof. Paola NARDINOCCHI

Aug – Dec 2014 Visiting Scholar at Boston University

Advisor: Prof. Douglas P. Holmes

October 2012 M.Sc. in Space Engineering, Sapienza - Università di Roma

10/110 cum laude

Thesis: "On the control of the large deformations occurring in IPMCs"

Advisor: Prof. Paola NARDINOCCHI

October 2010 B.Sc. in Aerospace Engineering, Sapienza - Università di Roma

110/110 cum laude

Thesis: "Bending deformations in ionic polymer metal composites induced by

mechano-electro-chemical interactions"

Advisor: Prof. Paola NARDINOCCHI

I

INVITED SEMINARS

- A Geometrically Exact Model for Thin Magneto-elastic Shells. Sapienza University of Rome, Rome, Italy, September.
- 2020 Towards Fluid-Shells Interactions. Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark, April.
- 2016 Geometry and Instabilities in Growing Shells. Sapienza Università di Roma, Rome, Italy, December.
- 2016 Geometry and Instabilities in Growing Shells. Physical Mathematics Seminar, MIT, Cambridge, MA, October
- Morphing of geometric composites. Form Finding Workshop, Roma Tre University, Rome, Italy, April.
- Morphing of Geometric Composites via Residual Swelling. Bertoldi Group Meeting, Harvard University, Cambridge, MA, December.

SUBMITTED PUBLICATIONS OR PUBLICATIONS IN PREPARATION

- P. G. Ledda, M. Pezzulla, and F. Gallaire. Gravity-driven coatings on generic substrates. *In preparation*
- M. Pezzulla, D. Yan, and P. M. Reis. A geometrically exact model for thin magneto-elastic shells. Submitted
- P. Leroy-Catalayud, M. Pezzulla, A. Keiser, K. Mulleners, and P. M. Reis. Tapered foils favor traveling-wave kinematics to enhance the performance of flapping propulsion. *Submitted*
- T. G. Sano, M. Pezzulla, and P. M. Reis. A Kirchhoff-like theory for hard magnetic rods under three-dimensional geometrically nonlinear deformation. *Submitted*. Avalaible at arXiv:2106.15189

JOURNALS & CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS

- B. Shrimali, M. Pezzulla, S. Poincloux, P. M. Reis, and O. Lopez-Pamies. The remarkable bending properties of perforated plates. *J. Mech. Phys. Solids* 154, 104514 (2021).
- D. Yan, M. Pezzulla, L. Cruveiller, A. Abbasi, and P. M. Reis. Magneto-active elastic shells with tunable buckling strength. *Nat. Commun.* 12, 2831 (2021).
- M. Pezzulla, E. F. Strong, F. Gallaire, and P. M. Reis. Deformation of porous flexible strip in low and moderate Reynolds number flows. *Phys. Rev. Fluids* 5, 084103 (2020)
- D. P. Holmes, J.-H. Lee, H. S. Park, and M. Pezzulla. The nonlinear buckling behavior of a complete spherical shell under uniform external pressure and homogenous natural curvature. *Phys. Rev. E* 102, 023003 (2020)
- D. Yan, M. Pezzulla, and P. M. Reis. Buckling of pressurized spherical shells containing a throughthickness defect. *J. Mech. Phys. Solids* 138, 103923 (2020)
- M. Pezzulla and P. M. Reis. A Weak Form Implementation of Nonlinear Axisymmetric Shell Equations with Examples. ASME. J. Appl. Mech. 86(12): 124502, (2019)
- E. F. Strong, M. Pezzulla, F. Gallaire, P. M. Reis, and L. Siconolfi. Hydrodynamic loading of perforated disks in creeping flows. *Phys. Rev. Fluids* 4, 084101, (2019)
- A. Lee, D. Yan, M. Pezzulla, D. P. Holmes, and P. M. Reis. Evolution of critical buckling conditions in imperfect bilayer shells through residual swelling. *Soft Matter* 15, 6134-6144, (2019)

- L. Stein-Montalvo, P. Costa, M. Pezzulla and D. P. Holmes. Buckling of Geometrically Confined Shells. *Soft Matter* 15, 1215-1222, (2019)
- 2018 X. Jiang, M. Pezzulla, S. Wei, T. K. Ghosh, and D. P. Holmes. Snapping of Bistable, Prestressed Cylindrical Shells. *Europhys. Lett.* 122, 64003, (2018)
- M. Pezzulla, N. Stoop, M. P. Steranka, A. J. Bade, and D. P. Holmes. Curvature-Induced Instabilities of Shells. *Phys. Rev. Lett.* 120, 048002, (2018)
- M. Pezzulla, N. Stoop, X. Jiang, and D. P. Holmes. Curvature-Driven Morphing of Non-Euclidean Shells. *Proc. R. Soc. A* 473(2201), 20170087, (2017)
- M. Pezzulla, G. P. Smith, P. Nardinocchi, and D. P. Holmes. Geometry and Mechanics of Thin Growing Bilayers. *Soft Matter* 12, 4435-4442, (2016)
- P. Nardinocchi, M. Pezzulla, and L. Teresi. Steady and transient analysis of anisotropic swelling in fibered gels. J. Appl. Phys. 118, 244904, (2015)
- M. Pezzulla, S. A. Shillig, P. Nardinocchi, and D. P. Holmes. Morphing of geometric composites via residual swelling. *Soft Matter* 11, 5812-5820, (2015) [Inside Front Cover]
- P. Nardinocchi, M. Pezzulla, and L. Teresi, Mechanics of bio-hybrid systems. *Procedia IUTAM* 12, pp. 145-153, (2015)
- P. Nardinocchi, M. Pezzulla, and L. Teresi, Anisotropic swelling of thin gel sheets. *Soft Matter* 11, 1492-1499, (2015)
- A. Lucantonio, P. Nardinocchi, and M. Pezzulla. Swelling-induced and controlled curving in layered gel beams. *Proc. R. Soc. A* 470(2171), 20140467, (2014)
- A. Lucantonio, P. Nardinocchi, M. Pezzulla, and L. Teresi. Multiphysics of bio-hybrid systems: shape control and electro-induced motion. *Smart Mater. Struct.* 23(4), 045043, (2014)
- P. Nardinocchi, M. Pezzulla, B.J. Akle, M. Guenther, and T. Wallmersperger. Actuation and buckling effects in IPMCs. *Proc. SPIE* 9056, (2014)
- Y. Cha, P. Nardinocchi, M. Pezzulla, and M. Porfiri. Giant displacements in IPMC-based structures: a preliminary study. Adv. Mat. Res. 745, 119–128, (2013)
- P.Nardinocchi and M. Pezzulla. Curled actuated shapes of ionic polymer metal composites. *J. Appl. Phys.* 113, 224906, (2013)
- P. Nardinocchi, M. Pezzulla, and L. Placidi. Thermodynamically based multiphysic modeling of ionic polymer metal composites. *J. Intel. Mat. Syst. Str.* 22(16), 1887–1897, (2011)

Honors

| 2016 | PHASME 2016 Travel Grant, ICAM (USD 1K), |
|-----------|---|
| 2014 | Research Project Grant <i>Giovani Ricercatori</i> , INdAM (€ 1.6K), "Corrugamento di travi bistrato di gel polimerico" |
| 2014 | Research Project Young Investigator Grant, Sapienza University (\leqslant 2K), "Shaping of bio-hybrid systems: reduced models and numerical simulations" |
| 2013-2015 | Graduate Research Fellowship, Italian Ministry of Education |
| 2012 | ADISU M.Sc. degree award |
| 2010 | ADISU B.Sc. degree award |
| 2007-2012 | ADISU scholarship |

TEACHING AND SERVICE

| 2021 | Course Beams and plates AU, Instructor |
|-----------|---|
| 2019 | Lectures on shells for the class on <i>Mechanics of Slender Structures</i> EPFL, Instructor: Prof. Pedro M. Reis |
| 2017 | Guest Lecture on the Buckling of Columns for the class on <i>Mechanics of Materials</i> Boston University, Instructor: Prof. Harold S. Park |
| 2015-2019 | Reviewer for Journal of Intelligent Materials Systems and Structures, Journal of Applied Mechanics, Proceedings of the Royal Society A, International Journal of Solids and Structures, Soft Matter |
| 2015 | Teaching Assistant for the class on <i>Mechanics of Solids and Structures</i> (Instructor: Prof. P. Nardinocchi) |
| 2012-2015 | Co-advisor for bachelor theses in Aerospace Engineering and master theses in Aeronautical Engineering (Advisor: Prof. P. Nardinocchi) |

Language & Programming Skills

- ★ Mother tongue: Italian. Fluent in English. C2 in French. B2 in Spanish. A2 in Danish.
- ★ Experience programming in C, Fortran, and Python.
- * Experience with mathematical software such as Matlab, Mathematica, LabView, LATEX.
- \star Experience with FE software such as COMSOL Multiphysics, ADINA, Nastran.
- ★ Experience with Adobe Illustrator, Blender, MeshLab, Paraview and ImageJ.

| | N≥• |
|------------|------|
| September, | 2021 |